BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
THE PEOPLE, GROUPS, PLACES, AND INCIDENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE PURELY FICTIONAL
الأشخاص والمجموعات والأماكن والحوادث في هذه الدراما خيالية حقًا
Send this traitor to the State Tribunal!
أرسل هذا الخائن لمحكمة الدولة!
Halt!
وقف!
Not to the State Tribunal.
ليس لمحكمة الدولة.
Lock him up in the Internal Prison.
حبسه في السجن الداخلي.
I will…
أنا سوف…
hold him responsible in the future.
حمله المسؤولية في المستقبل.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
Take him away!
يأخذه بعيدا!
BLOODY HEART EPISODE 14
الحلقة 14 الحلقة 4 من انمي قلب دموي
The subjects were beheaded?
تم قطع رؤوس الموضوعات؟
Councilor Park won't let that happen.
كونسيلور بارك لن يدع ذلك يحدث.
That's what I find even weirder.
هذا ما أجده أغرب.
Councilor tried to take the Queen Dowager's life
حاول المستشار أن يأخذ حياة الملكة الأرملة
and was put in the Internal Prison.
ووُضع في السجن الداخلي.
Councilor Park can't be that foolish.
لا يمكن أن تكون حديقة كونسيلور بهذه الحماقة.
But it seems to be true.
لكن يبدو أن هذا صحيح.
This is
هذا هو
simply tyranny.
ببساطة الاستبداد.
What did the State Council do?
ماذا فعل مجلس الدولة؟
What about the Three Offices, the Royal Family, and scholars?
وماذا عن المكاتب الثلاثة والعائلة المالكة والعلماء؟
They used the law, causes, and honor for parents
استخدموا القانون والأسباب والشرف للآباء
to stop me from making any moves.
لمنعني من القيام بأي تحركات.
Why are they silent now?
لماذا هم صامتون الآن؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I have another piece of news.
لدي خبر آخر.
Please don't move.
من فضلك لا تتحرك.
You should be careful right now.
يجب أن تكون حذرا الآن.
Have you heard?
هل سمعت؟
I heard…
سمعت…
you are pregnant.
انت حامل.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I put you through so much trouble even though you were pregnant.
أضعك في الكثير من المتاعب رغم أنك حامل.
I won't ever
لن افعل ابدا
leave you alone again.
اتركك بمفردك مرة أخرى.
Ttonggeum…
تنغيوم
died.
مات.
She died in my place
ماتت في مكاني
in the hands of those who tried to kill me.
بأيدي من حاول قتلي.
The Queen Dowager is a tyrant.
الملكة الأرملة طاغية.
An oppressor.
ظالم.
She cannot continue like this.
لا يمكنها الاستمرار على هذا النحو.
It may be dishonoring your mother,
قد يكون ذلك إهانة لأمك ،
but you must do this for our people and the Royal Family.
لكن يجب أن تفعل هذا من أجل شعبنا والعائلة المالكة.
You have no time to lose.
ليس لديك وقت لتخسره.
If her tyranny is prolonged,
إذا طال طغيانها ،
we don't know how much our people will suffer.
لا نعرف كم سيعاني شعبنا.
The Queen Dowager must be
يجب أن تكون الملكة الأرملة
deposed as soon as possible.
خلعه في أقرب وقت ممكن.
She annihilated a good number of subjects
لقد قضت على عدد لا بأس به من المواضيع
without questioning them once.
دون استجوابهم مرة واحدة.
Even Councilor Park is locked up in the Internal Prison.
حتى Councilor Park مسجون في السجن الداخلي.
That's the prison for eunuchs and court ladies.
هذا هو سجن الخصيان وسيدات المحاكم.
Turn a blind eye to it,
غض الطرف عنها ،
if you wish to live.
إذا كنت ترغب في العيش.
Inspector Park of the Office of Inspector General.
حديقة المفتش بمكتب المفتش العام.
Please allow me in.
من فضلك اسمح لي بالدخول.
There is a rumor
هناك شائعة
that Councilor Park is imprisoned in the Internal Prison.
أن كونسيلور بارك مسجون في السجن الداخلي.
Do you know
هل تعرف
anything about this?
أي شيء عن هذا؟
Please spare him, Your Highness.
أرجوك تعفيه ، صاحب السمو.
My lord does not have anything to do with this rebellion.
لا علاقة لسيدي بهذا التمرد.
And it is told that
ويقال ذلك
he dared to take your life,
لقد تجرأ على الانتحار ،
but he's only getting framed.
لكنه فقط تم وضعه في إطار.
You're asking me to spare him,
أنت تطلب مني أن أنقذه ،
which makes me want to kill him even more.
مما يجعلني أرغب في قتله أكثر.
I shall
على أن
cut off my tongue
اقطعوا لساني
since it dared to defy you.
لأنها تجرأت على تحديك.
If you ask me for my head,
إذا سألتني عن رأسي ،
I will give it to you.
سأعطيك اياه.
And how shall I use that disgusting thing?
وكيف يمكنني استخدام هذا الشيء المثير للاشمئزاز؟
Keep your eyes on everything
ابق عينيك على كل شيء
with the same vigor when you humiliated me.
بنفس الحماسة عندما أذللتني.
Your tongue, your head,
لسانك ، رأسك
and your life as the wife of the left state councilor.
وحياتك كزوجة عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر.
Mother, let us go.
أمي ، دعونا نذهب.
Go meet your father.
اذهب للقاء والدك.
The Internal Prison doesn't allow private visitors.
السجن الداخلي لا يسمح بالزوار الخاصين.
I'll find a way for you.
سأجد طريقة لك.
Go ask your father what he's up to.
اذهب واسأل والدك عما ينوي فعله.
I will do
سأفعل
as he asks.
كما يطلب.
TRAITOR
خائن
NO KYUNGMOON
لا كيونغ مون
Announcing that in these current times
الاعلان عن ذلك في هذه الاوقات الحالية
is the same as saying that you are.
هو نفس القول بأنك كذلك.
My lord.
ربي.
I became a bystander of slaughter
أصبحت متفرجًا على المذابح
although I was in charge of the palace's security.
على الرغم من أنني كنت مسؤولاً عن أمن القصر.
I let some hoodlums take the palace.
لقد تركت بعض الأشرار يأخذون القصر.
Did you not find any bodies?
ألم تجد أي جثث؟
No, they cleaned up everything after killing the hoodlums.
لا ، لقد قاموا بتنظيف كل شيء بعد قتل السفاحين.
It's not just a few.
انها ليست مجرد قلة.
That means the Consort is likely to have survived.
هذا يعني أنه من المحتمل أن يكون القرين قد نجا.
-Should I say I'm relieved? -My lord.
-هل أقول إنني مرتاح؟  -ربي.
Please look.
من فضلك انظر.
This was found nearby.
تم العثور على هذا في مكان قريب.
This is a wooden tag for a regional army.
هذه بطاقة خشبية لجيش إقليمي.
Does this mean
هل هذا يعني
regional soldiers are near the palace?
جنود المنطقة بالقرب من القصر؟
Did I disturb you from your sleep again?
هل أزعجتك من نومك مرة أخرى؟
I'll soon find out if the court ladies are fine.
سأكتشف قريبًا ما إذا كانت سيدات المحكمة بخير.
I told you not to worry about it.
قلت لك لا تقلق بشأن ذلك.
I keep dreaming
ما زلت أحلم
about how you spit out blood and collapsed before me.
حول كيف تبصق الدم وانهارت أمامي.
And Ttonggeum, right before her death.
و Ttonggeum ، قبل وفاتها مباشرة.
I keep telling myself that I cannot forget about her.
ما زلت أقول لنفسي أنني لا أستطيع أن أنساها.
Maybe that's why I keep seeing her.
ربما لهذا السبب أستمر في رؤيتها.
-We'll return to the palace soon. -Once we return,
- سنعود إلى القصر قريبا.  - بمجرد أن نعود ،
I'll find the one who tried to poison you to death.
سأجد الشخص الذي حاول أن يسممك حتى الموت.
The one who tried to hurt you
الشخص الذي حاول أن يؤذيك
might be the one behind the Queen Dowager.
قد تكون وراء الملكة الأرملة.
This isn't something she could have done alone.
هذا ليس شيئًا كان يمكن أن تفعله بمفردها.
This is someone
هذا شخص ما
who put the country in chaos by using her.
الذين وضعوا البلاد في حالة من الفوضى باستخدامها.
I will not forgive this one.
لن اسامح هذا.
I must have…
ينبغي ان أتوفر…
become weak.
تهنوا.
I have more to protect,
لدي المزيد لأحميه ،
and it only makes me more impatient and scared.
وهذا يجعلني أكثر نفاد صبرًا وخوفًا.
This must be why my late father
يجب أن يكون هذا هو سبب والدي الراحل
also cowered down.
أيضا منكمش.
I finally understand
فهمت في النهاية
how he felt.
كيف شعر.
What are you
ما أنت
so afraid of?
خائف جدا من؟
I was afraid I wouldn't be able to protect you.
كنت خائفة من أنني لن أستطيع حمايتك.
And now,
و الأن،
I'm afraid I may
أخشى أنني قد أفعل ذلك
lose you.
افتقدك.
I went through two selections
ذهبت من خلال تحديدين
to marry a strange man.
للزواج من رجل غريب.
And both times, it was with you.
وفي المرتين كان معك.
We were meant to be.
كنا من المفترض أن تكون.
We cannot be separated that easily.
لا يمكن الفصل بيننا بسهولة.
Were you
هل أنت
really going to kill me?
حقا سيقتلني؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
I am grieved that I could not take your life.
أنا حزين لأنني لم أستطع الانتحار.
Just as I dragged down the old deposed king,
مثلما جرّت الملك المعزول إلى أسفل ،
I will also drag you down.
أنا أيضا سوف أسحبك إلى أسفل.
A subject who rebels once is a vassal of merit,
الشخص الذي يتمرد مرة واحدة هو تابع للاستحقاق ،
but twice, they are a traitor.
لكن مرتين ، هم خونة.
Dragging down the Queen Dowager whilst in her regency?
سحب الملكة الأرملة إلى أسفل بينما هي في الوصاية على العرش؟
That is rebellion.
هذا هو التمرد.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I will become a traitor.
سأصبح خائنا.
You must have forgotten
يجب أن تكون قد نسيت
that you were locked up trying to murder royalty.
أنه تم حبسك وأنت تحاول قتل الملوك.
Your crime is enough to have three generations annihilated.
جريمتك تكفي لإبادة ثلاثة أجيال.
In that case, you can punish me according to our customs.
في هذه الحالة ، يمكنك معاقبتي وفقًا لعاداتنا.
I decide what the customs are!
أنا أقرر ما هي العادات!
Nobody…
لا أحد…
stands above the customs.
يقف فوق الجمارك.
You should step down
يجب عليك التنحي
before you are dragged down.
قبل أن يتم جرك إلى أسفل.
What can you do?
ما الذي تستطيع القيام به؟
Nobody in the Royal Court is on your side.
لا أحد في الديوان الملكي إلى جانبك.
Even if you die in here,
حتى لو مت هنا
nobody will step up for you.
لا أحد سيصعد من أجلك.
Before I die,
قبل أن أموت،
I will have you deposed, Your Highness.
سوف أقوم بخلعك يا صاحب السمو.
Where's Consort Park?
أين حديقة كونسورت؟
Is she alive or dead?
هل هي حية أم ميتة؟
Is somebody hiding her?
هل هناك من يخفيها؟
Maitreya has not answered.
مايتريا لم تجب.
You must have
يجب أن تمتلك
lost your power.
فقدت قوتك.
And where is my message of the King's death?
وأين رسالتي عن وفاة الملك؟
You continuously miss things,
تفوتك الأشياء باستمرار ،
so the chief eunuch had to send someone to the detached palace.
لذلك كان على رئيس الخصي أن يرسل شخصًا إلى القصر المنفصل.
If a scout is here,
إذا كان الكشاف هنا ،
it means the Queen Dowager is suspicious of me.
هذا يعني أن الملكة الأرملة تشك بي
Tell Siwol to stop going into the palace.
أخبر Siwol بالتوقف عن الذهاب إلى القصر.
We need someone to cause trouble with the Queen Dowager.
نحن بحاجة إلى شخص ما يسبب مشكلة مع الملكة الأرملة.
We cannot do that without Siwol.
لا يمكننا فعل ذلك بدون Siwol.
It'll take some time,
سيستغرق بعض الوقت ،
but it's doable.
لكنها قابلة للتنفيذ.
Kyun.
كيون.
I saw that kid's face.
رأيت وجه ذلك الطفل.
If he gets hurt,
إذا أصيب ،
I'll never be able
لن أكون قادرة على الإطلاق
to forget that boy's face.
لننسى وجه هذا الصبي.
And I only saw him once.
وأنا رأيته مرة واحدة فقط.
How would you feel?
كيف سيكون شعورك؟
If you came this far,
إذا وصلت إلى هذا الحد ،
the situation must be very dire.
يجب أن يكون الوضع رهيبا جدا.
Councilor Park knows about you.
كونسيلور بارك يعرف عنك.
Eunuchs are also keeping an eye on you,
الخصيان أيضا يراقبونك ،
so the chief eunuch is also suspicious of you.
فيشكك ايضا رئيس الخصي.
Everyone whom I planted in the palace has fled already,
كل من زرعته في القصر هرب بالفعل ،
so I can't find any details.
لذلك لا يمكنني العثور على أي تفاصيل.
So you must leave immediately too.
لذلك يجب عليك المغادرة على الفور أيضًا.
Father.
أب.
I thought
اعتقدت
after everything,
بعد كل شيء،
you would abandon me.
سوف تتخلى عني.
You have no use to me anymore,
لم يعد لديك استخدام لي بعد الآن ،
so of course, I'll abandon you.
لذلك بالطبع سوف أتخلى عنك.
He'll now tell the Queen Dowager that I am still alive.
سيخبر الآن الملكة الأرملة أنني ما زلت على قيد الحياة.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I sent Siwol away.
لقد أرسلت Siwol بعيدًا.
He should be out of the city by now.
يجب أن يكون خارج المدينة الآن.
Good job.
أحسنت.
Father, it's me.
أبي هو أنا.
I have one last thing to do before I leave.
لدي شيء أخير أفعله قبل أن أغادر.
Don't worry too much.
لا تقلق كثيرا.
You know,
أنت تعرف،
I'm glad I have a father
أنا سعيد لأن لدي أب
I can say that too.
أستطيع أن أقول ذلك أيضا.
The ones who took Consort Park dropped that.
أولئك الذين أخذوا Consort Park أسقطوا ذلك.
If you found the evidence, you should catch the Consort first.
إذا وجدت الدليل ، عليك أن تمسك بالقرينة أولاً.
Why are you so slow?
لماذا انت بطيء جدا؟
It's a regional army tag.
إنها علامة جيش إقليمية.
What?
ماذا؟
I do not know which region they are from,
لا أعرف من أي منطقة هم ،
but that position shows
لكن هذا الموقف يظهر
local soldiers under a governor are near the palace.
الجنود المحليين تحت الحاكم بالقرب من القصر.
We never mobilized a governor's soldiers, so…
لم نحشد أبدا جنود المحافظ ، لذا ...
If His Majesty gave an order,
إذا أمر جلالة الملك ،
it would've been possible.
كان من الممكن.
Why are you telling me this now?
لماذا تخبرني بهذا الآن؟
How dare that disgusting eunuch!
كيف يجرؤ هذا الخصي المثير للاشمئزاز!
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
There is bad news.
هناك أخبار سيئة.
The ones who took Consort Park
أولئك الذين استولوا على كونسورت بارك
seem to be local soldiers working for a governor.
يبدو أنهم جنود محليين يعملون لحساب حاكم.
I haven't told any governor to mobilize his soldiers lately.
لم أخبر أي محافظ أن يحشد جنوده في الآونة الأخيرة.
Why are they near the palace?
لماذا هم بالقرب من القصر؟
On top of that,
علاوة على ذلك ،
the troop dispatch token is still within palace walls.
رمز إرسال القوات لا يزال داخل جدران القصر.
If His Majesty signed the order,
إذا وقع جلالة الملك على الأمر ،
it might be possible.
قد يكون من الممكن.
It looks like
يبدو
His Majesty has woken up.
استيقظ جلالة الملك.
Hyekang said the King will not live.
قال Hyekang أن الملك لن يعيش.
He can miss everything else,
يمكنه أن يفتقد كل شيء آخر ،
but he was never wrong about…
لكنه لم يكن مخطئا بشأن ...
the King.
الملك.
Did you just say that my uncle is to be sent to Jeolla Province?
هل قلت للتو أنه سيتم إرسال عمي إلى مقاطعة جولا؟
You choose to send one of my few relatives
اخترت إرسال أحد أقاربي القلائل
so far away.
بعيد جدا.
His Majesty has
جلالة الملك
already appointed him as governor of Jeolla Province.
عينه بالفعل محافظا لمحافظة جولا.
To honor the skies before the rain-calling ceremony,
لتكريم السماء قبل مراسم نداء المطر ،
he lowered his food intake for the past three days.
قام بتخفيض كمية الطعام التي يتناولها خلال الأيام الثلاثة الماضية.
Since last night, he did not even drink water.
منذ الليلة الماضية ، لم يشرب الماء حتى.
That is true.
هذا صحيح.
Those who serve at his palace can testify to that.
ويمكن لمن يخدم في قصره أن يشهد على ذلك.
How peculiar.
كيف غريب.
He fasted, you say?
صام تقول؟
Not even the former King did as such.
ولا حتى الملك السابق فعل ذلك.
But yet, he somehow consumed poison.
لكن مع ذلك ، استهلك السم بطريقة ما.
Stop him.
أوقفوه.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
I have been away for too long.
لقد كنت بعيدا لفترة طويلة.
Hyekang.
Hyekang.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
Is there a possibility for the King to wake up?
هل هناك احتمال أن يستيقظ الملك؟
That will not happen.
هذا لن يحدث.
He's already about to go to the other side.
إنه بالفعل على وشك الذهاب إلى الجانب الآخر.
You dare…
تجروء…
deceive me?
يخدعني؟
Your Highness the Queen Dowager,
جلالة الملكة الأرملة ،
His Majesty has woken up.
استيقظ جلالة الملك.
I saw him walk around with my own two eyes.
رأيته يتجول بأم عينيّ.
I ask you once again.
أسألك مرة أخرى.
Has the King
له الملك
deceived me?
خدعتني؟
The King has…
الملك لديه ...
deceived me.
خدعتني.
The detached palace
القصر المنفصل
is protected by the soldiers
محمي من قبل الجنود
of the governor of Jeolla.
والي جولا.
I do not know!
لا أعلم!
All I heard was that
كل ما سمعته هو ذلك
they were mustered by a written order.
تم حشدهم بأمر مكتوب.
His Majesty will
وصية جلالة الملك
send the soldiers of Jeolla Province before him.
أرسل جنود محافظة جولا أمامه.
And he will
وسوف يفعل
take the palace over.
استولى على القصر.
He sent the troops here only with a written order?
أرسل القوات إلى هنا فقط بأمر مكتوب؟
He's more loyal to the Royal Family, even at the cost of his life.
إنه أكثر ولاءً للعائلة المالكة ، حتى على حساب حياته.
What shall you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
He sent the army here without the troop dispatch token,
أرسل الجيش هنا بدون رمز إرسال القوات ،
so this is treason.
لذلك هذه خيانة.
Go to the Office of Seals and Badges.
اذهب إلى مكتب الأختام والشارات.
I have the troop dispatch token to deploy the local army.
لدي رمز إرسال القوات لنشر الجيش المحلي.
I shall muster every single soldier of this nation
سأحشد كل جندي من هذه الأمة
to burn down
لحرق
the King's detached palace.
قصر الملك المنفصل.
Halt.
وقف.
The troop dispatch token belongs to the Ministry of Defense.
رمز إرسال القوات ينتمي إلى وزارة الدفاع.
It was only transferred to you in a state of emergency.
تم نقله إليك فقط في حالة الطوارئ.
But now, the Queen Dowager demands it.
ولكن الآن تطلبها الملكة الأرملة.
-You must obey her command. -How dare you.
-يجب أن تمتثل لأمرها.  -كيف تجرؤ.
-Do not speak to Minister Cho like that. -How dare you!
- لا تتحدث مع الوزير تشو بهذه الطريقة.  -كيف تجرؤ!
My order is the Queen Dowager's order.
طلبي هو أمر الملكة الأرملة.
I have evidence of some traitors
لدي دليل على بعض الخونة
surrounding his detached palace to plot treason
حول قصره المنفصل لمؤامرة الخيانة
against the King while he isn't in his right mind.
ضد الملك بينما هو ليس في عقله الصحيح.
I send the troop dispatch token.
أرسل رمز إرسال القوات.
All governors of Joseon shall send their soldiers immediately.
يجب على جميع حكام جوسون إرسال جنودهم على الفور.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The Queen Dowager mustered all soldiers in every province.
حشدت الملكة الأرملة جميع الجنود في كل مقاطعة.
She sent the fake token all around the provinces of Joseon.
أرسلت الرمز المزيف في جميع أنحاء مقاطعات جوسون.
The Queen Dowager finally showed her rebellious motives.
أظهرت الملكة الأرملة أخيرًا دوافعها المتمردة.
Send my order and the real tokens to the governors around the country
أرسل طلبي والرموز الحقيقية إلى المحافظين في جميع أنحاء البلاد
and muster the troops.
وحشد القوات.
Your order is my command.
طلبك هو أمري.
GOVERNOR OF HWANGHAE PROVINCE
محافظ مقاطعة هوانغا
Things are just as you predicted.
الأمور كما توقعت.
The Queen Dowager
الملكة الأرملة
took the troop dispatch token.
تولى رمز إرسال القوات.
I did everything as you said with the wooden tag
فعلت كل شيء كما قلته بالملصق الخشبي
and the troop dispatch token.
ورمز إرسال القوات.
So tell me now.
لذا قل لي الآن.
Has His Majesty
صاحب الجلالة
woken up?
استيقظ؟
Yes.
نعم.
You don't look too thrilled about His Majesty's return.
لا تبدو مبتهجًا جدًا بعودة صاحب الجلالة.
I am in charge of the palace's security,
أنا مسؤول عن أمن القصر ،
yet I failed to carry out my duty.
ومع ذلك فشلت في القيام بواجبي.
How will I pay for my sin?
كيف سأدفع ثمن ذنبي؟
I am a little afraid.
انا خائف قليلا
Minister Cho, you should make a contribution.
معالي الوزير تشو ، يجب عليك تقديم مساهمة.
But I do not think you'll have too much time to think.
لكن لا أعتقد أنه سيكون لديك الكثير من الوقت للتفكير.
Councilor Park, what are you scheming in there?
كونسيلور بارك ، ما الذي تخطط له هناك؟
I'm trying to help His Majesty get what he wants.
أحاول مساعدة جلالة الملك في الحصول على ما يريد.
Telling the world that
اخبر العالم بذلك
the Queen Dowager is a traitor.
الملكة الأرملة خائنة.
And now, the times will become tough
والآن ، ستصبح الأوقات صعبة
for the Queen Dowager and her subjects.
للملكة الأرملة ورعاياها.
Inspector Park!
المفتش بارك!
Will you really hand in that appeal to the Queen Dowager?
هل ستسلم هذا النداء حقًا إلى الملكة الأرملة؟
Please move aside.
الرجاء التحرك جانبا.
Stop being so naive.
توقف عن السذاجة.
Even the Left Minister was killed. What can you do?
حتى الوزير اليساري قتل.  ما الذي تستطيع القيام به؟
Your father is also imprisoned in the Internal Prison.
والدك مسجون أيضا في السجن الداخلي.
You are the one who taught me that the Three Offices must lay down our lives.
أنت من علمني أن المكاتب الثلاثة يجب أن تضع حياتنا.
If I was only worried about staying alive,
إذا كنت قلقة فقط بشأن البقاء على قيد الحياة ،
I would also turn in my appeal, at the risk of my family's annihilation.
أود أيضًا أن أقدم طلب الاستئناف الذي قدّمته لخطر إبادة عائلتي.
Her Highness is making an attempt to change the system of the Three Offices.
تحاول سموها تغيير نظام المكاتب الثلاثة.
I cannot let her bring down the Three Offices.
لا يمكنني السماح لها بإسقاط المكاتب الثلاثة.
The Three Offices have already fallen.
لقد سقطت المكاتب الثلاثة بالفعل.
If the troops of Jeolla's governor are protecting
إذا كانت قوات حاكم جولا تحمي
the crafters of Bamboo Grove Village,
حرفيو قرية بامبو جروف ،
it must be His Majesty.
يجب أن يكون صاحب الجلالة.
I'm not sure how far His Majesty is involved.
لست متأكدًا من مدى مشاركة جلالة الملك.
I'm not sure if the troops in the city are on the Queen Dowager's order…
لست متأكدًا مما إذا كانت القوات في المدينة بأمر من الملكة الأرملة ...
or His Majesty's.
أو صاحب الجلالة.
Which side do you hope they are?
في أي جانب تأمل أن يكونوا؟
APPEAL
مناشدة
Whether I should consider you your father's child
هل يجب أن أعتبرك طفل والدك
or your mother's child…
أو طفل والدتك ...
I was once troubled over it.
لقد كنت مضطربًا ذات مرة بسبب ذلك.
Treat me as inspector of the Office of Inspector General.
عاملني كمفتش في مكتب المفتش العام.
Did you think this appeal would work in any way?
هل تعتقد أن هذا النداء سيعمل بأي شكل من الأشكال؟
Even if it does not,
حتى لو لم يحدث ذلك ،
my duty is to turn it in again and again,
واجبي هو تسليمها مرارا وتكرارا ،
whether it be ten times or twenty.
سواء كانت عشر أو عشرين.
I'd rather have you beg me to let your father go.
أفضل أن أتوسل إلي لأطلق سراح والدك.
If he has committed a crime, he must be punished.
إذا ارتكب جريمة وجب معاقبته.
That is my father's business.
هذا هو عمل والدي.
From the Office of Inspector General I, Inspector Park Namsang, ask of you.
من مكتب المفتش العام الأول ، أسأل المفتش بارك نامسانغ.
The tyranny of the Queen Dowager worsens day by day.
استبداد الملكة الأرملة يزداد سوءًا يومًا بعد يوم.
Also, a group of cunning eunuchs is
أيضا ، مجموعة من الخصيان الماكرة
working with a pagan religion to even disrupt political affairs.
العمل مع دين وثني لتعطيل الشؤون السياسية.
They assume power, threaten local leaders,
إنهم يتولون السلطة ويهددون القادة المحليين ،
and even extort civilian farmlands and their women.
بل وحتى ابتزاز الأراضي الزراعية المدنية ونسائهم.
All those with common sense have come together
لقد اجتمع كل من يتمتعون بالفطرة السليمة
to denounce the Queen Dowager.
للتنديد بالملكة الأرملة.
Drag Inspector Park out immediately!
اسحب المفتش بارك للخارج على الفور!
WEST GATE
البوابة الغربية
They have committed all these crimes with the Queen Dowager behind them.
لقد ارتكبوا كل هذه الجرائم مع الملكة الأرملة من ورائهم.
Their crimes must be exposed in every detail--
يجب الكشف عن جرائمهم بكل التفاصيل -
Inspector Park, enough!
بارك المفتش ، كفى!
Your Highness!
صاحب السمو!
His Majesty has come into the city.
لقد جاء جلالة الملك إلى المدينة.
How did the King come into the city?
كيف دخل الملك المدينة؟
The governor of Gyeonggi is here along with His Majesty.
حاكم "كيونجي" موجود هنا مع جلالة الملك.
Call Minister Cho now.
اتصل بالوزير تشو الآن.
Tell him to close all gates
قل له أن يغلق كل البوابات
and not to let anybody in.
وعدم السماح لأي شخص بالدخول.
Open up the palace gates!
افتح بوابات القصر!
His Majesty has returned!
لقد عاد جلالة الملك!
Drop your swords.
أسقط سيوفك.
His Majesty commands it.
جلالة الملك يأمر بذلك.
Tie up all eunuchs.
اربط كل الخصيان.
Make sure the court ladies do not leave.
تأكد من أن سيدات المحكمة لا يغادرن.
-Yes!
-نعم!  -نعم!
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I'm very glad as your mother
أنا سعيدة جدا كأمك
to see how healthy you have become.
لمعرفة مدى صحتك.
I heard
سمعت
you have been troubled because of me.
كنت مضطربا من أجلي.
Mother.
الأم.
You are…
أنت…
stepping on the King's road.
تخطو على طريق الملك.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
drag me off it.
اسحبني منها.
Go ahead and dishonor your mother and provide a good reason
امض قدمًا وأهين والدتك وقدم سببًا وجيهًا
for your political enemies.
لأعدائك السياسيين.
If you shed a drop of my blood,
إذا سفكت قطرة من دمي ،
you won't be able to keep your throne.
لن تكون قادرًا على الاحتفاظ بعرشك.
I am still…
لا زلت…
your mother.
والدتك.
Your Highness, I am a court lady of the King's Palace.
صاحب السمو ، أنا سيدة بلاط في قصر الملك.
Put me down.
انزلني.
THIRD INNER GATE
البوابة الداخلية الثالثة
Do you know what happened to the ladies of Chaeokdang?
هل تعرف ماذا حدث لسيدات تشايوكدانج؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
You were all right.
كنت بخير.
Thank you so much for staying alive.
شكرا جزيلا لك على البقاء على قيد الحياة.
The King has returned.
لقد عاد الملك.
What do you hope will happen to me?
ماذا تأمل أن يحدث لي؟
After high treason,
بعد الخيانة العظمى ،
the people threw stones on the wicked woman's body
كان الشعب يرشقون جسد المرأة الشريرة بالحجارة
which became her grave.
الذي صار قبرها.
Then the deposed king died in a hut without a single ray of sunlight
ثم مات الملك المخلوع في كوخ دون شعاع واحد من ضوء الشمس
all alone.
وحيد للغاية.
That is only reasonable.
هذا فقط معقول.
Bad news.
اخبار سيئة.
I'm not like the deposed king.
أنا لست مثل الملك المخلوع.
He was a king,
كان ملكا
but I am
ولكن انا
the Queen Dowager.
الملكة الأرملة.
The King has deceived me.
لقد خدعني الملك.
Did you know about this?
هل تعلم عن هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
If I trusted you more than I had,
إذا وثقت بك أكثر مما كنت ،
would things have changed?
هل ستتغير الأشياء؟
I do not think
لا اعتقد
things would have been different.
كان من الممكن أن تكون الأمور مختلفة.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Even the female physician said His Majesty cannot wake up anymore.
حتى الطبيبة قالت إن جلالة الملك لا يستطيع الاستيقاظ بعد الآن.
Do you wish for His Majesty to pass away?
هل تتمنى وفاة جلالة الملك؟
No, how could I…
لا ، كيف يمكنني ...
But Father,
لكن أبي ،
I am also scared of myself.
أنا أيضا خائف من نفسي.
How can I meet His Majesty with this sinful face?
كيف ألتقي جلالة الملك بهذا الوجه الخاطئ؟
I couldn't possibly show my face even in the afterlife.
لم أستطع إظهار وجهي حتى في الحياة الآخرة.
I shouldn't have
لا يجب أن أمتلك
turned in your profile for the selection.
تحولت في ملف التعريف الخاص بك للاختيار.
Come out.
يظهر.
His Majesty ordered your release.
أمر جلالة الملك بالإفراج عنك.
Please get dressed properly.
يرجى ارتداء الملابس المناسبة.
I will run your bath.
سأدير حمامك.
Thank you, my lady.
شكرا سيدتي.
Siwol.
سيوول.
I told you to travel far.
أخبرتك أن تسافر بعيدًا.
Why are you laying here?
لماذا ترقد هنا؟
Get up. Let us go home.
استيقظ.  دعونا نعود إلى المنزل.
Let's go home, Siwol.
دعنا نذهب للمنزل ، Siwol.
Siwol.
سيوول.
Open your eyes, Siwol.
افتح عينيك يا سيوول.
Let's go home.
لنذهب إلى المنزل.
Siwol.
سيوول.
You can't lie here like this.
لا يمكنك الكذب هنا هكذا.
So Ttonggeum was buried in that forest?
إذن تم دفن Ttonggeum في تلك الغابة؟
Yes.
نعم.
I asked the court ladies whom I trained.
سألت سيدات المحكمة اللاتي قمت بتدريبهن.
They couldn't take her out of the city.
لم يتمكنوا من إخراجها من المدينة.
They have done well.
لقد عملوا بشكل جيد.
I should be able to give her a funeral soon.
يجب أن أكون قادرًا على منحها جنازة قريبًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Thanks to you, I got to say goodbye to her.
شكرا لك ، يجب أن أقول لها وداعا.
Are they yet to capture Eunuch Heo?
هل لم يلقوا القبض على الخصي هيو بعد؟
How can I
كيف يمكنني
leave the palace?
اترك القصر؟
I no longer have anywhere to hide.
لم يعد لدي أي مكان للاختباء فيه.
All troops are looking for him.
كل القوات تبحث عنه.
Eunuch Heo took a noble family's house, took in a mistress,
أخذ الخصي هيو منزل عائلة نبيلة ، واستولى على عشيقته ،
and even set other houses on fire,
وحتى أشعلوا النار في منازل أخرى ،
so they will not lose him.
حتى لا يفقدوه.
A court lady saw him running into the library.
رأته سيدة المحكمة يركض إلى المكتبة.
Eunuch Heo must have caught Ttonggeum in the secret passage.
يجب أن يكون الخصي هيو قد قبض على Ttonggeum في الممر السري.
It means he knows the passage is in the library.
هذا يعني أنه يعرف أن المقطع موجود في المكتبة.
He'll hide there and wait until things become quiet.
سوف يختبئ هناك وينتظر حتى تهدأ الأمور.
He'll be arrested soon. Please return to your dwelling.
سيتم القبض عليه قريبا.  يرجى العودة إلى مسكنك.
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
Will you go over yourself?
سوف تذهب على نفسك؟
I cannot let him die…
لا أستطيع تركه يموت ...
in peace.
بسلام.
I'll send him over to Siwol
سأرسله إلى Siwol
as payment for his way to the other side.
كدفعة لطريقه إلى الجانب الآخر.
Block off all exits of the passage.
أغلق جميع مخارج الممر.
I will never
لن أفعل أبدا
use that passage again.
استخدم هذا المقطع مرة أخرى.
Never.
أبداً.
Excuse me! Open this door!
اعذرني!  افتح هذا الباب!
There is someone inside!
هناك شخص ما بالداخل!
The things that happened while I was unconscious is
الأشياء التي حدثت عندما كنت فاقدًا للوعي هي
utterly wretched.
بائس تماما.
Taking the troop dispatch token
أخذ رمز إرسال القوات
and creating a fake one to deceive the governors all around
وإنشاء صورة مزيفة لخداع الحكام في كل مكان
is clearly and obviously
بشكل واضح وواضح
a rebellion.
تمرد.
And everything was committed
وكان كل شيء ملتزمًا
with my mother as the leader, although she has no business in politics.
مع والدتي كقائدة ، رغم أنها لا تعمل في السياسة.
This is a heinous crime that cannot be forgiven.
هذه جريمة شنعاء لا يمكن التسامح معها.
Arrest all those who created the Interrogation Bureau
القبض على كل من أنشأ مكتب الاستجواب
and took part in the rebellion.
وشارك في التمرد.
Even if you are a subject of merit, according to your crimes,
حتى لو كنت موضوع الاستحقاق حسب جرائمك ،
their honor will be stripped
سيتم تجريد شرفهم
and the land and slaves they received will be taken away.
وتأخذ الارض والعبيد التي اخذوها.
Also, those who contributed greatly
أيضا ، أولئك الذين ساهموا بشكل كبير
in subduing this rebellion will be complimented,
في إخضاع هذا التمرد سيُثنى عليه ،
and they will also receive an office.
وسيحصلون أيضًا على مكتب.
Moon Simhyun is the leader of the Sarim in Songrim.
Moon Simhyun هو زعيم Sarim في Songrim.
How can he be the Left Minister?
كيف يكون الوزير اليساري؟
What is this shocking appointment?
ما هو هذا الموعد الصادم؟
He might change the three state councilors too.
قد يغير أعضاء مجلس الدولة الثلاثة أيضًا.
Will you let him continue?
هل تسمح له بالاستمرار؟
Yes.
نعم.
We should let him.
يجب أن نسمح له.
This is our time to put up with this.
هذا هو وقتنا لتحمل هذا.
His Majesty will continue with the criminals, create justifications,
سيستمر جلالة الملك مع المجرمين ويخلق المبررات ،
and take away the order of merit from all of his subjects.
وسحب وسام الاستحقاق من جميع رعاياه.
Yes.
نعم.
We will let him do this.
سوف نتركه يفعل هذا.
Why won't you hold Councilor Park responsible?
لماذا لا تحملين "كونسيلور بارك" المسؤولية؟
Is it
فعلا
because of me?
بسببي؟
No.
رقم.
I have enough evidence that he tried to kill the Queen Dowager.
لدي أدلة كافية أنه حاول قتل الملكة الأرملة.
I can accuse him whenever I must.
يمكنني أن أتهمه متى لزم الأمر.
I can put it off for a while.
يمكنني تأجيلها لفترة من الوقت.
I will use him
سأستخدمه
as a hunting dog.
ككلب صيد.
Write down the names of the traitors who rebelled against me
اكتب أسماء الخونة الذين تمردوا علي
by taking advantage of the Queen Dowager.
من خلال الاستفادة من الملكة الأرملة.
Everyone on this list will be eliminated, even if they are a subject of merit
سيتم استبعاد كل فرد في هذه القائمة ، حتى لو كان موضوعًا للجدارة
or a member of the Royal Family.
أو أحد أفراد العائلة المالكة.
I'm sure there is someone who convinced her to do this.
أنا متأكد من أن هناك شخصًا أقنعها بفعل هذا.
A woman cannot commit such an atrocious act
لا يمكن للمرأة أن ترتكب مثل هذا العمل الشنيع
all by herself.
كل ذلك بنفسها.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I wish to speak to you alone.
أتمنى أن أتحدث معك وحدك.
You may.
يمكنك.
Who do you wish to take out?
من الذي ترغب في إخراجه؟
The late king, my father, gave merit to the subjects
أعطى الملك الراحل ، والدي ، مزايا للرعايا
according to the list the subjects made.
وفقا لقائمة الموضوعات.
I shall also punish those on the list
سأعاقب أيضا أولئك الموجودين في القائمة
according to our customs.
حسب عاداتنا.
How far do you wish to punish?
إلى أي مدى تريد أن تعاقب؟
I can't finish it with a slap on the wrist.
لا أستطيع أن أنهي الأمر بصفعة على معصمي.
After the limbs
بعد الأطراف
come the head.
تعال رأسك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
If you wish to lose just the limbs,
إذا كنت ترغب في فقدان الأطراف فقط ،
bring me the Queen Dowager.
أحضر لي الملكة الأرملة.
I will treat the Queen Dowager with honor
سأعامل الملكة الأرملة بشرف
until the very end.
حتى النهاية.
I cannot dishonor my mother
لا أستطيع إهانة والدتي
and give cause to start a rebellion.
وإعطاء سبب لبدء التمرد.
So you subjects must step up
لذلك يجب أن تتقدم الموضوعات
and depose my mother.
وخلع والدتي.
That is
هذا هو
how you will get to keep
كيف ستحصل على
your petty lives.
حياتكم التافهة.
I, Left State Councilor Park Gyewon,
أنا ، عضو مجلس الدولة الأيسر بارك جيون ،
accept His Majesty's order as my command!
تقبل بأمر جلالة الملك كما أمري!
I will…
أنا سوف…
depose the Queen Dowager!
خلع الملكة الأرملة!
You survived once again, thanks to your father.
لقد نجوت مرة أخرى بفضل والدك.
Your luck
حظك
will not last long.
لن تستمر طويلا.
Councilor Park's power has fallen.
سقطت سلطة كونسلور بارك.
How can you last any longer?
كيف يمكنك الاستمرار لفترة أطول؟
You caused Ttonggeum's death.
لقد تسببت في وفاة Ttonggeum.
One day, I will make you pay for her death.
ذات يوم ، سأجعلك تدفع ثمن موتها.
After my installation ceremony,
بعد حفل التثبيت الخاص بي ،
I will treat you as the Queen does a concubine and subject.
سوف أعاملك كما تفعل الملكة محظية وموضوع.
What have I done wrong?
مالخطأ الذي فعلته؟
You're a fake.
كنت وهمية.
You deceived the world and the Royal Family.
لقد خدعت العالم والعائلة المالكة.
His Majesty may keep the crafters safe,
جلالة الملك قد يحافظ على سلامة الحرفيين ،
but that fact won't change.
لكن هذه الحقيقة لن تتغير.
The crafters are…
الحرفيون ...
kept safe by his Majesty?
جلالة الملك؟
My father has kept an eye on them, so he's well aware of this.
كان والدي يراقبهم ، لذا فهو يدرك ذلك جيدًا.
When Eunuch Heo tried to take them in,
عندما حاول Eunuch Heo استيعابهم ،
the troops of a governor kept them safe, didn't they?
قوات الوالي تحافظ على سلامتهم ، أليس كذلك؟
Let's see how long His Majesty will
دعونا نرى إلى متى سوف جلالة الملك
keep you safe.
تبقيك آمنا.
How did His Majesty
كيف فعل جلالة الملك
know the crafters would fall in danger
أعلم أن الحرفيين سيقعون في خطر
and kept them safe?
وحافظت على سلامتهم؟
Is His Majesty in bed?
هل جلالة الملك في الفراش؟
No, he's still in his royal office.
لا ، لا يزال في مكتبه الملكي.
It seems like he will be late, so please come in.
يبدو أنه سيتأخر ، لذا تفضل بالدخول.
I will wait here.
سأنتظر هنا.
He gave me the order
أعطاني الأمر
to escort you in immediately no matter when you come.
لمرافقتك على الفور بغض النظر عن وقت مجيئك.
Is Consort Park here?
هل كونسورت بارك هنا؟
She is, Your Majesty.
هي يا جلالة الملك.
Consort Park.
كونسورت بارك.
There were subjects who did not show up…
كان هناك أشخاص لم يحضروا ...
during the regency of the Queen Dowager.
خلال فترة حكم الملكة الأرملة.
Left Minister No Kyungmoon.
وزير اليسار نو كيونغمون.
Minister of Taxation Park Chanwe.
وزير الضرائب بارك تشانوي.
Left Vice Minister Ko Inhyuk.
نائب الوزير الأيسر كو اينهيوك.
Minister of Commerce Im Joyong.
وزير التجارة Im Joyong.
I have seen
لقد رأيت
this arrangement before.
هذا الترتيب من قبل.
I saw it before you collapsed.
رأيته قبل أن تنهار.
The one who caused the regency by the Queen Dowager,
الذي تسبب في الوصاية على العرش من قبل الملكة الأرملة ،
the one who shook this nation and let it fall in danger was…
الذي هز هذه الأمة وتركها في خطر كان ...
you…
أنت…
and your design?
والتصميم الخاص بك؟
BLOODY HEART
قلب دموي
Ttonggeum has died.
لقد مات Ttonggeum.
She died because of your scheming.
ماتت بسبب مكائدك.
They are not to be dealt with by justice and righteousness alone.
لا ينبغي التعامل معهم بالعدل والاستقامة فقط.
Please step down on your own.
يرجى التنحي بمفردك.
His Majesty wishes for your death.
جلالة الملك يتمنى موتك.
Deposement will not be enough.
لن يكون الإيداع كافياً.
She will once again use filial duty to pressure me.
سوف تستخدم واجب الأبناء مرة أخرى للضغط علي.
Will you have her assassinated?
هل ستقتلها؟
I would have done the same if I were King.
كنت سأفعل الشيء نفسه لو كنت ملكًا.
His Majesty and I are very much alike.
جلالة الملك وأنا متشابهان إلى حد كبير.
His Majesty is nothing like you.
جلالة الملك ليس مثلك.
He shall be different.
يجب أن يكون مختلفا.
And so, I will…
وهكذا ، سأفعل ...
keep His Majesty in check.
إبقاء جلالة الملك تحت السيطرة.
Translated by Eun-sook Yoon
ترجمه أون سوك يون